Alexey Smirnov

Frontend Developer

Kyiv +38(063)328-28-64 alexey@smirnov.works github.com/xLEWKANx t.me/xLEWKANx

About me

All my life I've wanted to create something meaningful. That's why I went to university to study electronics. When I burned several microcircuits I realized that I'm a better software engineer than a hardware one. I've started learning JavaScript and due to it's cross-platform nature I've spent most of the time creating products in the first place. In 7 years of using it, I've created <u>online music radio</u>, a mobile application for iOS and Android, one documentation, one cross-platform library, one UI system, several dashboards, multiple simple backend services, a lot of web resources and tons of infographics.

Employment History

Head of Development at LP/AD (Canada)

November 2020 - August 2021

LP/AD is a boutique brand consultancy that specializes in helping businesses with strategy, positioning, launch, re-launch or repositioning of their brand(s).

Responsibilities

- Develop landing websites using Gatsby + Headless CMS
- Develop and support e-commerce websites with Shopify
- Consulting with UI/UX solutions for long term usage
- Choosing hosting solutions and post-launch support
- Consult and integrate 3rd party solutions and services

Works

- Love map for MTRSS band
 - Map builded with D3 and React
 - Data parsed from Spotify Artist Dashboard
 - Backend written with Fastify for Node.JS
 - Backend secured and hosted on DigitalOcean
 - Generating postcards on the backend and with social sharing

• Vindica website

- Made online website constructor based on Prismic CMS and React Components
- Other websites
 - o https://sonderly.io/ (Gatsby + Prismic CMS)
 - https://elabsinc.netlify.app/ (Gatsby + Headless Wordpress)

Team Lead at Virgil Security Inc. (USA)

August 2017 - August 2020

Virgil Security, Inc. enables developers to eliminate passwords & encrypt everything, in hours, without having to become security experts.

Responsibilities

- Leading the JavaScript team and some product features
- Developed and maintained company's Front-End resources (website, documentation and dashboard)
- Developed (<u>e3kit</u> lib) and maintained (<u>crypto</u> and <u>sdk</u> libs) company's JavaScript open source tools
- Created demos for Node.JS, React Native, Ionic and Browsers using company's SDKs
- Provided integrations with Twilio, Firebase and Stripe services

Full-Stack developer at iPublisher (Ukraine)

November 2015 - July 2017

Small developers-only company doing all kinds of projects using JavaScript.

Responsibilities

- Made app for gasoline company Avias on <u>Android</u> and iOS
- Created admin dashboard for Ukrainian political party (NDA)
- Builded interactive map of Ukraine with plain JavaScript and GeoJSON (NDA)
- Created tons of infographics for political party using mongoDB aggregations for their data (NDA)

Professional Skills

- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, QT QML, looking into learning Python.
- 2. **Frameworks:** React, Node.JS, React Native, Express, Loopback, able to learn any framework.
- 3. Static site generators: Gatsby, Next.js.
- 4. **JS Libraries**: MobX, Redux, React Spring, React Use Gesture, D3, but prefer not to use extra libraries.
- 5. **JS Tools:** Lerna, Babel, Webpack, Rollup for web apps and libraries bundling.
- 6. **CSS Frameworks:** Bootstrap, Less/Sass, CSS Modules, Styled Components, depending on the use case.
- 7. **Databases:** MySQL, mongoDB able to configure, secure, create relations, write queries, etc.
- 8. Services: Firebase, Stripe, Twilio, Auth0, Shopify.
- **9. Design:** I love Figma (especially components), using it to design something before implementing it.
- **10. Paradigms:** OOP (I've never met another working paradigm in real life, unfortunately).

Education

2010 - 2014 Bachelors degree at National Technical University of Ukraine *«Kyiv Polytechnic Institute»*, Electronics faculty.

- Designed, created and populated the <u>website</u> for my department.

Hobbies

- **Sports:** acrobatics, crossfit, yoga, trampoline jumping, surfing.
- Music: like to attend live concerts, playing piano and guitar, want to create electronic music.
- Other: Exploring ancient places, old-school tattoos and old-school cars, longboards and e-scooters.